Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Faculty Publications, 1844-1994 RG.1.1
New York University Archives
New York University Archives Collection of Faculty Publications
1822-2015
New York University Archives
New York University
RG.1.1
24.25 Linear Feet in 29 boxes
The items in this collection represent a sample of published works by New York University professors and lecturers.
Arrangement
Works were boxed in approximate alphabetical order by author's last name. The files are grouped into one series:
I. Publications
Scope and Content Note
This collection is housed in 29 boxes, which can contain anywhere from 9 to 24 items. Materials range in publication date from 1844 to 1994, with the bulk of documents in the early to mid-twentieth century. The various publications cover all manner of topics in the humanities, social sciences, physical sciences, and other fields. A brief listing includes history, economics, religion, mathematics, politics and political science, physics, and sociology, although there are many more. Most of the documents included in this collection are articles and books concerning these fields and others, but there are a large number of biographies of various people. Documents are not organized chronologically, thematically, or alphabetically.
The following list displays some of the authors which appear often in this collection. Their works do not make up the majority of the collection, but their names are more prevalent:
Marshall W. Baldwin
Mary Elizabeth Barnicle
William Allen Butler
Elmer Elsworth Brown
Gay Wilson Allen
Henry M. Baird
Henry Pratt Fairchild
John William Draper
Thomas C. Cochran
Abraham I. Katsh
Henry Mitchell MacCracken
William H. Stahl
Ernest G. Sihler
Myron W. Watkins
Historical/Biographical Note
New York University is an academic institution and, as such, its faculty produces articles and books in their respective fields. This collection is an assortment of writings created by various people from multiple fields, indicating the extensive academic work completed by scholars throughout NYU's history. Maintaining these writings fulfills the mission statement of the University Archives in two ways: first, by providing a final repository for NYU-related records, and second, by documenting the intellectual history of the University through the physical preservation of materials.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Books.; Articles.; Biography.; Research (document genres).; New York University -- History
- Faculty Publications
  - Bevington, Merle Mowbray; The Saturday Review, 1855-1868: Representative Educated Opinion in Victorian England, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226986 3
  - Baldwin, Marshall W.; "The Papacy and the Levant During the 12th Century," Bulletin of the Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences in America, Jan 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adkins, Nelson Frederick; Fitz-Greene Halleck: An Early Knickerbocker Wit and Poet, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bayer, Henry G.; The Belgians: First Settlers in New York and the Middle States (2 copies), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Barnicle, Mary Elizabeth; The Seege or Baytle of Troye: A Mid-English Metrical Romance, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bell, Derrick; Confronting Authority: Reflections of an Ardent Protester, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Binder, Rudolph M.; Religion as Man's Completion, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Beals, R.A., Barnicle, M.E., and Terry, J.S.; Readings in Description and Narration, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adam, Thomas R.; Education for International Understanding, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Burnham, James; The Managerial Revolution: What Is Happening in the World, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226987 1
  - Butler, William Allen; Two Millions, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clapp, Edwin J.; Economic Aspects of the War, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cheney, Ralph Holt; Coffee, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Church, Austin H.; Centrifugal Pumps and Blowers, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Clapp, Edwin J.; The Port of Hamburg, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ed. Brown, Francis J. and Ed. Roucek, Joseph Slaby; Our Racial and National Minorities, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Butler, William Allen; A Retrospect of Forty Years 1825-1865, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Clapp, Edwin J.; Britifches Geefriesrecht und die Neutralen im Ariege 1914-16, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Butler, William Allen; The Revision of the Statutes of the State of New York and the Revisers, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stoddard, Francis Hovey; The Life and Letters of Charles Butler, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cochran, Thomas C.; New York in the Confederation, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Charvat, William; The Origins of American Critical Thought 1810-1835 (2 copies), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cartinhour, Gaines Thompson; Branch, Group, and Chain Banking, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brown,Francis James, Hodges, Charles, and Roucek, Joseph Slaby; Contemporary World Politics, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cochran, Thomas C.; The Pabst Brewing Company: The History of American Business, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Carpenter, Jesse T.; The South as a Conscious Minority, 1789-1861 (2copies), 1930 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Backman, Jules; Demand for Personal Credit in 1970, Mar 1966 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Baldwin, Marshall W.; "The Popes and Learning in the High Middle Ages," Manuscripta, Oct 1957 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Backman, Jules; The Heller Budget in Wage Negotiations, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Allen, B.S.; Anthology (Bound Reprints), 1916-1922 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226988 9
  - Baldwin, Marshall W.; Raymind the Third of Tripolus and the Fall of Jerusalem 1140-1187, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Brameld, Theodore; Design for America, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth; Government by Influence and Other Addresses (4 copies), 1910 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ed. Boulton, Archibald L.; Matthew Arnold: Prose and Poetry, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Allen, Gay Wilson; Walt Whitman Handbook, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth, Materials Regarding, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ed., Arndt, Christian O. and Everett, Samuel; Education for a World Society: Promising Practices Today, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Allen, Jerome; Temperament in Education, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Arnold, J. Loring; Concise Technical Physics, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Obligation of Universities to the Social Order (Collection of Addresses from 1932 Conference at NYU) (2 copies), 1933 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brademas, John; Washington D.C. to Washington Square, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Brisco, Norris A. Principles of Retailing, 1929 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth; A Few Remarks (2 copies), 1933 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Allem, Beverly Sprague; Tides in English Taste 1619-1800 (2 volumes), 1937 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Allen, Gay Wilson; William James: A Biography, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Allen, Gay Wilson; "Walt Whitman the Man" (lecture), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Allen, Gay Wilson; The Solitary Singer: A Critical Biography of Walt Whitman, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Adler, G.J.; History of Provencal Poetry (translated from the French by Adler), 1860 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Ed. Backman, Jules; Entrepreneurship and the Outlook for America, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226989 7
  - Ballard, Addison; Arrows (3 copies), 1890 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Baldwin, Marshall W.; The Medieval Church, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ed. Blum, David L.; Some NYU Verse (3 copies), 1926 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bader, Louis and Picker, Sidney; Marketing Drugs and Cosmetics, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Backman, Jules; Competition in the Chemical Industry, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Backman, Jules; Steel Prices, The Steel Industry, and the National Economy, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Baird, Henry Martyn; Theodore Beza: The Counselor of the French Reformation, 1899 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth; The Making of Our Middle Schools (2 copies), 1902 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ed. Baldwin, Marshall W.; A History of the Crusades, Vol. I: The First Hundred Years, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Baker, Paul R.; Richard Morris Hunt, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Berkman, Tessie D.; Practice of Social Workers in Psychiatric Hospitals and Clinics, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Bakeless, John; Daniel Boone: Master of the Wilderness, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Baldwin, Marshall W., Hayes, Carlton J.H., and Cole, Charles Woolsey; History of Europe, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Bakeless, John; Lewis and Clark: Partners in Discovery, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Baird, Henry M.; History of the Rise of the Huguenots of France, 1883 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bader, Louis; World Developments in the Cotton Industry, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Bobst, Elmer Holmes; Bobst: The Autobiography of a Pharmaceutical Pioneer, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226990 5
  - Cartter, Allan M.; An Assessment of Quality in Graduate Education, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Chase, Carl T.; Frontiers of Science, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Ed. Bouton, Archibald Lewis; The Lincoln and Douglas Debates, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Borgman, Albert S.; The Life and Death of William Mountfort, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stoddard, Francis Hovey; The Life and Letters of Charles Butler, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Haeger, John Denis; The Investment Frontier, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Charvat, William and Kraus, Michael; William Hickling Prescott, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Casson, Lionel and Hettich, Ernest L.; Excavations at Nessana, Vol. 2 Literary Papyri (2 copies), 1950 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Essays and Studies in Honor of Carleton Brown (Compilation) (2 copies), 1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth; A Few Remarks (5 copies), 1933 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Borgman, Albert S.; Thomas Shadwell: His Life and Comedies (2 copies), 1928 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bruun, Geoffrey; Europe and the French Imperium 1799-1814, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt; People: The Quantity and Quality of Population (2 copies), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226991 3
  - Bryans, William R. and Gus, Charles E.; Resistance of Materials and Theories of Structures, Part I, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth; Victory and Other Verse (2 copies), 1923 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Draper, John William; History of the Intellectual Development of Europe, 2 Volumes, 1878 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Edwards, George W.; Investing on Foreign Securities, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Ehret, William F.; Laboratory Studies in General Chemistry, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Ergang, Robert; The Potsdam Fuhrer, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Ergang, Robert; Europe from the Renaissance to Waterloo, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt; The Melting-Pot Mistake (2 copies), 1929 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt; The Foundations of Social Life, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt; Profits or Prosperity?, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fagg, John Edwin; The Republican Movement in Spain 1790-1868, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Draper, John W.; History of the American Civil War (Vol. 3), 1870 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Downs, Robert B.; Resources of Southern Libraries, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Ed. Draper; John W.; Elements of Chemistry (Robert Kane), 1843 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt; Economics for the Millions, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Billheimer, Albert; "Amendments in Athenian Decrees" American Journal of Archaeology, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Erim, Kenan T.; Aphrodisias: City of Venus Aphrodite, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Ewing, Frank; America's Forgotten Statesman: Albert Gallatin, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226992 1
  - Fairchild, Henry Pratt, ed.; Immigrant Backgrounds, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fleming, Donald; John William Draper and the Religion of Science, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Walters, Raymond, Jr.; Albert Gallatin: Jeffersonian Financier and Diplomat, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Fielding, Henry; The Adventures of Joseph Andrews, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Certain Letters of James Howell, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Heaton, H.C.; The Gloria d'Amour of Fra Rocaberti, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Crafts, Leland W., Schneirla, Theodore C., Robinson, Elsa E., Gilbert, Ralph W.; Recent Experiments in Psychology, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Dunbar, Howard Hunter; The Dramatic Career of Arthur Murphy, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Draper, John William; William Mason: A Study in 18th Century Culture, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Goldwater, Robert J.; Primitivism in Modern Painting, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Colin, David H., Girard, Richard A., Frederich, A. Anton, MacDonald, Lois, Stein, Emanuel; American Economic Behavior, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Draper, John William; Civil Policy of America (2 copies), 1865 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Brose, Henry L., trans; The Elements of New Quantum Mechanics (Otto Halpern and Hans Thurring), 1931 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Haywood, Richard Mansfield; The Myth of Rome's Fall, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Hall, Basil Douglas; The Life of Charles Cuthbert Hall: One Among a Thousand, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Gitlow, Abraham L.; Economics, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Grannis, Ruth Shepard; The Work of a Book Club (address for the Washington Square College Book Club of NYU), 1937 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Gitlow, Abraham L.; Labor and Industrial Society, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Draper, John William; History of the Conflict Between Religion and Science (Vol. 12) (2 copies), 1875 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226993 9
  - Gillett, E.H.; Ancient Cities and Empires: Their Prophetic Doom (2 copies), 1867 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Crosby, Howard; Expository Notes on the Book of Joshua (3 copies), 1875 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Draper, John William; The Civil War in America (Vol. 1 and 2), 1867-1868 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Draper, John William; Thoughts on the Future Civil Policy of America, 1865 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Gillett, E.H.; Life Lessons in the School of Christian Duty, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Downs, Robert B.; Resources of New York City Libraries, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Cochran, Thomas C., ed.; The Medici Bank: Its Organization, Management, Operations, and Decline, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Draper, John William; The Funeral Elegy and the Rise of English Romanticism, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Van Norden, Warner M.; The Fatness of Thy House, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Edmondson, T.W.; On the Disruptive Discharge in Air and Liquid Dielectrics, 1898 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Crosby, Howard; Memorial Papers and Reminiscences, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Eagleton, Clyde; The United Nations and the United States, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Eagleton, Clyde; The Responsibility of States and International Law, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Dunner, Joseph, Norton, Robert Homer, Godshall, Wilson Leon, Pletcher, David M., Zurcher, Arnold J.; Major Aspects of International Politics, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Edwards, George W.; International Trade Finance, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Mallery, Richard D., ed.; Master Works of Autobiography: Digests of Ten Great Classics, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226996 2
  - Lengyel, Emile; Dakkar: Outpost of Two Hemispheres, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Morison, Samuel Eliot; The Growth of the American Republic, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226994 7
  - Cummings, Thos. S.; Historic Annals of the National Academy of Design, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Courant, Richard; What Is Mathematics?, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Craven, Wesley Frank; Dissolution of the Virginia Company: The Failure of the Colonial Experiment (2 copies), 1932 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Donovan, Herbert D.A.; The Barn-Burners, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Craven, Wesley Frank; The Southern Colonies in the Seventeenth Century (1697-1689), 1949 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Cox, Richard T.; Time, Space, and Atoms, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Craven, Wesley Frank; An Introduction to the History of Bermuda (2 copies), 1938 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Craven, Wesley Frank; The Journal of Richard Norwood, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Medina, Jose Toribio; The Discovery of the Amazon, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Craven, Wesley Frank, ed.; The Army Air Forces in World War II (Vol. 1 and 3), 1948-1951 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Lewis, Tayler; The Six Days of Creation (2 copies), 1855 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226995 4
  - MacCracken, Henry Mitchell; Lives of the Leaders of Our Church Universal, 1879 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Johnson, E.A., ed.; Oratio Pro A. Cluentio Avito, Ad Judices, 1844 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Isaacs, Abram S.; Stories from the Rabbis, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood; Poems at 50 Years, 1880-1930, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cameron, Kenneth M., Hoffman, Theodore J.C.; The Theatrical Response, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Kelliher, Alice; Talks with Teachers, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Holzknecht, Karl J.; The Backgrounds of Shakespeare's Plays, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Institute of International Finance Bulletin (published by Graduate School of Business Administration, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Hering, D.W.; The Lure of the Clock (3 copies), 1932 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Hotchkiss, George Burton, ed.; A Treatise of Commerce (by John Wheeler) (3 copies), 1931 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Hindle, Brooke; The Pursuit of Science in Revolutionary America, 1735-1789, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Hering, Daniel W.; Essentials of Physics for College Students, 1912 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Hook, Sidney, Convitz, Milton R., eds; Freedom and Experience (essays presented to Horace Kallen), 1947 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Ben'Yoseph, Yaacov; The Dreamer and the Accomplisher, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Lilley, Ernest Raymond; The Geology of Petroleum and Natural Gas, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Isaacs, Edith J.R., ed.; Architecture for the New Theater, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Korff, Serge A.; The Origin and Implications of Cosmic Radiation, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Lilley, Ernest Raymond; Economic Geology of Mineral Deposits, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Hotson, Leslie; The Commonwealth and Restoration Stage, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Hettich, Ernest L.; A Study in Ancient Nationalism: The Testimony of Euripides (2 copies), 1933 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Jackson, Samuel Macauley; Huldreich Zwingli: The Reformer of German Switzerland, 1901 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Joselin, B.F.; Observations on the Tails of Halley's Comet, 1835 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Katsh, Abraham I.; "From the Moscow Manuscript of David Ha-Nagid's Midrash on Genesis" from *The Jewish Quarterly Review*, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Hilberri, Norman; Extensive Cosmic Ray Showers and the Energy Distribution of Primary Cosmic Rays, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Picard, Maurice; Values Immediate and Contributory and Their Interrelation, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Klemin, Alexander; If You Want to Fly: The Boy's Book of Aviation, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Juran, J.M.; Bureaucracy: A Challenge to Better Management, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Jones, Theodore F.; The New York University Collection (address prepared for the Washington Square Book Club), 1938 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Rapport, Samuel, Wright, Helen, eds.; Archaeology, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Rapport, Samuel, Wright, Helen, eds.; Engineering, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Rapport, Samuel, Wright, Helen, eds.; Mathematics, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Swabey, Marie Collins; Logic and Nature, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Hill, A.E.; Miscellaneous Publications in Chemistry, 1930-1940 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Katsh, Abraham I.; Catalog of Hebrew Manuscripts Preserved in the U.S.S.R. (2 copies) (Part II), 1958 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Swingle, W.W., Helff, O.M., Zwemer, R.L.; various articles about amphibians, 1925-1935 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Ludwig, Daniel; various articles about beetles, 1930-1940 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Howley, Frank L.; Your War for Peace, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04226997 0
  - Horne, Herman Harrell; The Philosophy of Education, 1927 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Jackson, Samuel Macauley; The Source of "Jerusalem the Golden", 1910 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Swabey, William Curtis; Being and Being Known (2 copies), 1937 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Rader, Paul; Professor Wilmess Must Die, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Henry Mitchell MacCracken: In Memoriam, 1923 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Raushenbush, Carl, Stein, Emanuel, eds.; Labor Cases and Materials, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Keliher, Alice; Life and Growth, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Henry, C.S.; Social Welfare and Human Progress, 1861 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hering, D.W.; Key to the Watches in the James Arthur Collection, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Draper, John William; Scientific Memoirs, 1878 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Hering, D.W.; Foibles and Fallacies of Science, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Knedler, J.W., Jr.; The Girl Without Hands: Latin American Variants, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Langstaff, John Brett; The Enterprising Life: John McVickar, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Keliher, Alice; A Critical Study of Homogeneous Grouping, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Korff, Serge A.; Electron and Nuclear Counters, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Hoag, J. Barton, Korff, Serge A. (rev.); Electron and Nuclear Physics, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Knedler, John Warren; Master Works of Science: Digest of 13 Great Classics, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Howley, Frank L.; Berlin Command, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Howley, Frank L.; Peoples and Policies: A World Travelogue, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Chase, C.T., Cox, R.T.; The Scattering of Fifty Kilo-Volt Electrons by Aluminum, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Myers, F.E., Byrne, J.F., Cox, R.T.; Diffraction of Electrons as a Search for Polarization, 1934 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Cox, R.T.; McIlwraith, C.G., Kurrelmeyer, B.; Apparent Evidence of Polarization in a Beam of Beta Rays, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Davis, T.W.; Solubility of Strontium Chromate and the Detection of Strontium, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Fagg, John E.; An Autobiographical Novel by Rafael Altamira, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Fowkes, Robert A.; The Phonology of Gaulish, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Coates, C.W., Cox, R.T., Granath, L.P.; The Electric Discharge of the Electric Eel, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Coates, C.W., Cox, R.T., Rosenblith, W.A., Brown, M. Vertner; Propagation of the Electric Impulse Along the Organs of the Electric Eel, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Burton, Milton, Davis, Thomas W., Gordon, Alvin, Taylor, H. Austin; The Photolysis of Ketene and the Structure of Methylene, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Davis, Thomas W., Burton, Milton; The Potential Energy Relationships in Normal and Excited Acetaldehyde, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Lucas, Henry C., Jr.; The Analysis, Design, and Implementation of Information Systems, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227013 5
  - Lounsbury, Ralph Greenlee; The British Fishery at Newfoundland, 1634-1763, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Park, Joseph H.; The English Reform Bill of 1867 (2 copies), 1920 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Park, Joseph H.; The English Working Men and the American Civil War (2 copies), 1924 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Lounsbury, Ralph Greenlee; Yankee Trade at Newfoundland (from the New England Quarterly), 1930 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Parker, Richard; Some Additional Sources of Dumas' Les Trois Musketeres (from Modern Philology), 1944 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Landgraf, John L.; Land Use in the Ramah Area of New Mexico: An Anthropological Approach to the Aerial Study, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Heaton, Harry Clifton; Another Pieza de Titulos de Comedias, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Heaton, Harry Clifton; Lope de Vega's Part 27 Extravagant, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 9)